A Guide to the Booton Herndon Papers, 1939-1986
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
The Booton Herndon Papers, 1939-1986
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9859-a
ca. 10,000 items (56 Hollinger boxes, 18 linear shelf feet)
The papers, 1939-1986, of Booton Herndon (1915- ) a free-lance writer of Charlottesville, Virginia, contain typed and autograph manuscripts of his books and articles, correspondence, business papers, research notes and outlines, photographs, printed material, and miscellany.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Mr. Booton Herndon of Charlottesville, Virginia, gave his papers to the Library on August 31, 1987.
Biographical Information
Booth Herndon (1915- ) has been a reporter, editor, public relations consultant, free-lance writer, ghost writer, and a contributor of several hundred articles and short stories to national magazines.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains Booton Herndon's working files of manuscripts for his books and articles together with related research material, correspondence, drafts, illustrative material and some proof. This collection is particularly useful in showing the various stages of production of an article or book by a professional writer.
There are files for projected books on the American Civil Liberties Union and Mortimer Caplin, Internal Revenue commissioner, and for an unpublished novel, "Splendor in the grass" as well as books on the Ford family and motor company, Leggett's department stores, Fulton Lewis, Jr., James A. Reed, and exercise. Frequent topics for articles include sports, particularly football, World War II, and Charlottesville and Albemarle County, Virginia. Of interest is an article by Paul Gaston and Thomas Hamond on public school desegregation in Charlottesville, Virginia.
Correspondents include Patty Duke Astin, Roger N. Baldwin, Mortimer Caplin, Arthur Hailey, Dorothy Kenyon, Fulton Lewis, Jr., Littauer and Wilkinson, Robert D. Loomis, Eddie Rickenbacker, William B. Spong, Max Wilkinson, and Babe Zaharias.
Arrangement
Arrangement
These papers are arranged chronologically within each topical folder, maintaining Herndon's original organization whenever possible. A small group of unpublished manuscripts of fiction and non-fiction articles compose a separate series at the end of the collection.
Organization
Herndon's papers have been divided into two series. Series I, Alphabetical Files, is a topical arrangement of his working files of various ideas for stories, articles, and books. Each file contains all of the material pertinent to its own subject whether correspondence, research material, illustrative material, or manuscript. A few of the more frequent correspondents will be listed with the folder name in which they appear, and if necessary, with dates of their letters. Series II, Miscellaneous Articles & Stories, consists of several folders of unpublished manuscripts by Herndon.
Frequent or Notable Correspondents:
Max Wilkinson (1904-1985), a partner of Littauer and Wilkinson, and an agent for Booton Herndon
Alan Ameche (1956 April 18)
ACLU: Book Correspondence (1960 December 6)
"Big Week" (1961 April 27)
Book Possibilities (1959 March 30, September 3; 1960 April 12, August 18; 1961 August 18, 24, 30; 1963 June 7; 1964 March 26; n.y. August 20)
Boston (1954 February 10)
Caplin: Correspondence (1964 January 27, February 13, March 20, April 29; 1965 September 30; 1966 November 21)
Charleston, South Carolina (1957 March 6, April 10)
Coles, Pauline (1953 October 14, December 14, 28; 1954 February 15, April 12)
Coroners (1954 August 4)
Daniels, Dr. Sophia (1953 July 15; n.d.)
Drunk Driving (1956 August 28)
Duchin, Eddy (1951 November 27)
Everett, Elinor (1956 September 14)
Foote Mineral Company (1956 September 14)
Ford: Correspondence (1967 August 4)
Hall, James W. (1960 January 5)
Helicopters (1958 June 13, 18)
Highways (1953 July 17)
"How to Build..." (1956 March 26)
"How to Invest $ 10,000" (1957 February 21)
Irvin, Mrs. Monty (1954 April 8, 20)
Isometrics (1966 March 4, 9)
Jenks, Jackson (1960 January 5)
Kelly, Alma (n.d.)
"Let's Trade Texas..." (1964 September 3)
Littauer and Wilkinson (entire folder)
Outer Banks (1956 September 24)
Personal Correspondence (1968 August 29)
Praised and Damned Correspondence (1953 December 21; 1954 April 12, May 18, July 28)
Rickenbacker (1967 December 8; 1968 February 14, March 27, May 28, August 2,15, September 4)
St. Martin's Press (1962 November 13)
Speed Trap (1956 January 5, 10, 11)
"Splendor in the Grass" (1966 October 24)
Story Ideas (1962 November 29)
SAC (1961 December 8)
Treasury Department (1956 May 18)
Welsh, Miriam (1967 December 4)
Zaharias, Babe (1953 June 30)
True Magazine, edited by Douglas S. Kennedy & Don McKinney
Ameche, Alan (1956 March 21)
ACLU: The American Legion ([1961] March 3)
ACLU: Correspondence (1959 October 2)
ACLU: True Magazine(1960 March 25, April 13)
Anderson, Frederick (1961 February 7)
Boyer family (1956 August 9)
Bright, Johnny (1959 December 29; 1960 January 18, March 30)
Burnelli, Vincent (1961 August 4, October 19; 1962 July 17)
Carolina Basketball (1957 January 30, April 8)
Correspondence (1957 December 2)
Durant, William (1958 January 15, May 7)
Eaton, Cyrus (1957 May 24)
Etcheverry, Sam (1961 April 17, March 24)
Gifford, Frank (1961)
Hall, James W. (1958 December 10; 1959 January 7, 15, April 28, May 14, December 8; 1962 January 9)
Hamby, Gordon Fawcett (1962 June 22)
Helicopters (1958 May 13)
Iceland (1963 February 28, April 30, June 5, August 23, September 10; 1964 January 23)
Jenks, Jackson (1958 April 29, July 23, August 20, September 25, October 2)
Le Baron, Eddie (1957 October 29; 1958 February 20, April 3, 8)
McGuire, Frank (1961 April 12)
Milner, Dumas (1957 September 23)
Minneapolis Lakers (1959 August 19; 1960 February 8)
Ocean Shipping (1958 February 25)
Peterson, Dick (1959 June 19, July 31; 1960 October 31)
Quinine (1963 October 31; 1964 February 17, 27, March 10, June 17)
Slocum, Harvey (1957 April 23, December 16; 1958 January 15, 21, 22, March 3, 19, July 2)
Story Ideas (1965 December 9; 1967 June 8)
Wildcatting (1958 January 29, February 14, August 7; 1959 February 25)
Saturday Evening Post
Caplin: Correspondence (1962 October 2, December 4; 1963 January 16, February 14, 28, March 14)
Helicopters (1958 June 12, August 28, December 18; 1959 January 15, November 12)
"How to Build..." (1956 April 9, 12, 21, June 8, 19)
Jenks, Jackson (1959 March 26, April 29, June 11, 15, July 10, 17)
Miller School (1954 June 11)
"Mortimer Caplin..." (1963 February 6)
National Urban League (1956 December 7)
Saga edited by Ed Fitzgerald, Al Silverman, etc.
Balchen, Col. Bernt (1957 May 21)
Boeing B-17 (1960 November 7)
Cagle, Chris (1956 November 15)
Collins, Floyd (1956 January 17)
Correspondence (1957 December 3)
"The Day the Boys..." (1959 May 15, 20, July 7)
Dexter, Harry (1955 September 19)
Korean War Heroes (1963 March 8, May 13)
Okinawa (1959 December 18)
Outer Baldonia (1952 November 11)
Private Eyes (1955 September 20)
Puller, General Lewis (1963 January 11)
St. Louis (1960 April 8)
Seventh Cavalry (1961 March 24)
Traitors (1960 September 15)
Van Orden, George (1952 January 25, February 13, March 5)
Correspondents in ACLU files
Angell, Ernst ACLU: Correspondence (1962 November 5) Baldwin, Roger Nash (1884-1981) ACLU: Baldwin (n.d.); ACLU: Book Organization, memo by Baldwin (1946 October 8); ACLU: History (1946 October 8); ACLU: Index to Cases (1960 March 28)
Heisler, Francis ACLU: True article (1959 Jul 30, November 3)
Kenyon, Dorothy ACLU: Correspondence (1961 September 15, October 26; 1962 March 26)
Loomis, Robert D. (Random House editor) re a possible book concerning the history of the ACLU, which was never published because of financial difficulties and a similiar book written by Charles Lee Markham entitled The Noblest Cry, A History of the ACLU. ACLU: Book Correspondence (1961 February 1); ACLU: Correspondence (1961 October 10, November 3; 1962 June 15, 20, September 27; 1963 April 11, December 26; 1964 January 14, November 25; 1971 June 15, 24, July 15, 28)
Miscellaneous Correspondents
Caplin, Mortimer book - ACLU: Correspondence (1963 December 26)
Duke, Patty - Olivier, Sir Laurence (1961 November 10)
free-lance writing difficulties - Dvorak, August (1956 June 2)
Gladding International Sport Fishing Museum, South Otselic, New York - Public Relations (1970)
Hailey, Arthur (1920- ) - Ford: Correspondence (1969 December 15)
Lewis, Fulton, Jr. - Praised and Damned (1954 September 23)
McNally, John - Johnny Blood (1953 October 7)
Rickenbacker, Edward V. - Rickenbacker Correspondence (1967 Christmas; 1969 April)
Spong, William B., Jr. - Personal Correspondence (1969 April 30)
Zaharias, Babe - (1953 September 9)
Contents List
- Alphabetical Files (Box 1-53)
  - "Adventure Behind the Lens" - Prospectus n.d. (Box 1)
  - Air Force Short Story Contest 1962 (Box 1)
  - Airplanes and Flight Research Material 1957-1960 (Box 1)
  - Al and Dick's House ("Tin Pan Alley Relocated") 1953, 1955, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Ameche, Alan and Williamson, Ivan (Wisconson Football) 1954 (Box 1)
  - Ameche, Alan (Part 2 - Baltimore Colts) 1956 (Box 1)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU): Achievments and Failures n.d. (Box 1)
  - ACLU: Affiliates n.d. (Box 1)
  - ACLU: The American Legion 1954-1961 (Box 1)
  - ACLU: Baldwin, Roger 1953 (Box 1)
  - ACLU: Bienniel Conference 1960 (Box 1)
  - ACLU: Book Correspondence 1960-1963, n.d. (Box 1)
  - ACLU: Book Organization 1946, n.d. (Box 1)
  - ACLU: Books re ACLU n.d. (Box 2)
  - ACLU: Buckley, William & Gerald Smith n.d. (Box 2)
  - ACLU: Bulletins and Newsletters 1959-1962 (Box 2)
  - ACLU: Bulletins and News Releases 1964-1968, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - ACLU: Case Descriptions and Notes 1957, 1960, n.d., 3 folders (Box 2)
  - ACLU: Censorship 1951-1961 (Box 3)
  - ACLU: Civil Liberties Union of Massachusetts 1945 (Box 3)
  - ACLU: Committees n.d. (Box 3)
  - ACLU: Communist Influence n.d. (Box 3)
  - Continuing Battles 1961 (Box 3)
  - ACLU: Correspondence 1959-1964, 1968, 1971 (Box 3)
  - ACLU: General Information n.d. (Box 3)
  - ACLU: History 1939, 1946 (Box 3)
  - ACLU: History of Development n.d. (Box 3)
  - ACLU: House Un-American Activities Committee 1958-1961, n.d. (Box 3)
  - ACLU: Index to American Civil Liberties Cases 1954-1960 (Box 3)
  - ACLU: International League for the Rights of Man n.d. (Box 3)
  - ACLU: Labor Industry n.d. (Box 3)
  - ACLU: McCarthyism 20's - 50's 1961, n.d. (Box 4)
  - ACLU: Michigan Trip 1959-1961, n.d. (Box 4)
  - ACLU: Misc. (notes) 1961-1963 (Box 4)
  - ACLU: Obstacles n.d. (Box 4)
  - ACLU: Operation Abolition 1960-1961 (Box 4)
  - ACLU: Police Practices 1954-1963 (Box 4)
  - ACLU: The Press n.d. (Box 4)
  - ACLU: Publications (w/pictures and drawings) 1941 (Box 4)
  - ACLU: Publications ca. 1945 (Box 4)
  - ACLU: Race Relations 1960-1961 (Box 4)
  - ACLU: Related Organizations n.d. (Box 4)
  - ACLU: Religion in Schools 1959-1963 (Box 4)
  - ACLU: Religious Freedom 1959-1961 (Box 5)
  - ACLU: Reports 1960-1962, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Rights of Undesirables 1958-1961 (Box 5)
  - ACLU: George Rockwell 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - ACLU: St. Louis Civil Liberties Union 1948-1961 (Box 5)
  - ACLU: Schools and Free Speech 1959-1962 (Box 5)
  - ACLU: Staff ca. 1945 (Box 5)
  - ACLU: Thompson, Sam 1959-1960 (Box 6)
  - ACLU: True Magazine Article 1947, 1959-1961 (Box 6)
  - ACLU: Various Leads 1955-1961 (Box 6)
  - ACLU: Wartime n.d. (Box 6)
  - American Medical Association (AMA) - Welfare Fund Story, Correspondence & Reports 1952-1959 (Box 6)
  - AMA Notes & Research n.d. (Box 6)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP) and Broadcast Music, Inc. (BMI) - Backround Info. ca. 1957 (Box 6)
  - ASCAP & BMI - Correspondence and related articles 1957-1958 (Box 6)
  - The American Weekly- Articles by Booton Herndon 1946-1951, n.d., 3 folders (Box 7)
  - The American Weekly- Typed Manuscripts 1946, n.d. (Box 7)
  - The American Weekly- Typed Manuscripts, Carbons 1946-1951, n.d., 2 folders (Box 7)
  - The American Weekly- Typed Manuscripts, Carbons n.d. (Box 8)
  - Anderson, Major General Frederick L. ( True Article) 1960-1961 (Box 8)
  - Anzio Landing in Italy 1960 (Box 8)
  - Atlantic City General Hopsital - Visiting Chiefs Program 1955 (Box 8)
  - Bakhtiar, James Abol Hassan (Virginia Football) 1956-1957 (Box 8)
  - Balchen, Col. Bernt 1957 (Box 8)
  - Baldwin Locomotive 1958 (Box 8)
  - "Bergdorf's on the Plaza" - A Musical Comedy 1960 (Box 8)
  - "Bigger Digger of the Red Wiggler" 1967, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - "Big Week" (unpublished book) 1960-1962, 1967 (Box 8)
  - "Billion-Dollar Garbage Man" 1967-1968 (Box 8)
  - Blackburn College 1952-1952 (Box 9)
  - Black Jaguar 1968 (Box 9)
  - Blood, Johnny 1953 (Box 9)
  - Bloodhound Stories 1946-1948 (Box 9)
  - Blue Ridge School 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Boeing B-17 1960 (Box 9)
  - Book Possibilities 1957-1967 (Box 9)
  - "Born A Fighter" - the George S. Patton, Jr. Story n.d. (Box 9)
  - Boston 1954 (Box 9)
  - Boxing Story n.d. (Box 9)
  - Boyer Family 1956 (Box 9)
  - Bridge and Tunnel Builders 1958 (Box 9)
  - Bright, Johnny 1959-1960 (Box 9)
  - Brooklyn 1953 (Box 9)
  - Browning, Getty (Blue Ridge Parkway) 1951-1952 (Box 9)
  - Burnelli, Vincent 1961-1962, 1965 (Box 10)
  - Business Administration (U.Va. Business School) 1956 (Box 10)
  - Business Correspondence 1968-1969 (Box 10)
  - Cagle, Chris 1956 (Box 10)
  - Camp Faith 1967-1968 (Box 10)
  - Canada - Victor 1971 (Box 10)
  - Canadian Football 1959-1960 (Box 10)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Correspondence 1962-1969, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Manuscript - Rough Draft Chapters I-XVI, XXX 1965, n.d., 7 folders (Box 11)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Manuscript - Chapters I-XVI n.d., 8 folders (Box 12)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Administration 1961-1964, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - The American Tax System, general 1960-1964, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Audit Packet (Public Information Division) 1963 (Box 13)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Automatic Data Processing (ADP) 1961-1964 (Box 13)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Boxing 1962, 1964 (Box 14)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Caplin Interview by Herndon n.d. (Box 14)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Career Prior to Being Commissioner of the Internal Revenue Service 1958, n.d. (Box 14)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Compromises, Settlements 1962, n.d. (Box 14)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Corruption 1961, 1964-1965 (Box 14)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Cuba 1961-1963 (Box 14)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Enforcement 1958-1964 (Box 14)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Expense Accounts ca. 1958-1965, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Farewell articles, speeches and notes 1963-1965 (Box 15)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Reseach Material - Forms, Public Relations and Teaching Taxes 1961-1964 (Box 15)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Foundation's Impact on Small Business 1964 (Box 15)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Gambling 1961-1962, 1964 (Box 15)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - General Information n.d. (Box 15)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Ingegrity 1961-1963 (Box 15)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Integrity 1964, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Internal Revenue Service 1960-1964 (Box 16)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Legislative Process n.d. (Box 16)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Misc. 1961-1965 (Box 16)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Myths re Entertainers 1963-1964 (Box 16)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - New Direction 1961-1964 (Box 16)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - New Tax Laws 1961-1965 (Box 17)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Office of International Operations (OIO) 1961-1963, 1964 (Box 17)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - OIO, Trip to Europe 1961-1964, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Organized Crime Crive 1958-1965, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material = Personal Profiles and Background 1961-1963 (Box 18)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Protests, Opposition 1960-1964 (Box 18)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Rulings 1963-1965 (Box 18)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Speeches 1961-1964 (Box 18)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Tax Exempt Foundations and Gifts 1961-1964, n.d., 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Taxpayer Compliance Measurement Program (TCMP) 1962-1963 (Box 19)
  - Caplin, Mortimer: Research Material - Unusual Problems with the IRS 1964 (Box 19)
  - Carolina Basketball 1957 (Box 19)
  - Charleston, S.C. 1957 (Box 19)
  - Chinchillas 1956 (Box 19)
  - Chincoteague 1957-1958 (Box 19)
  - Chosin Reservoir n.d. (Box 19)
  - Christian Rural Overseas Program (CROP) 1956 (Box 19)
  - Clearing Contractors 1952 (Box 19)
  - Clients - Correspondence, Biographical Data re: Booton Herndon 1958-1959, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Coles, Pauline 1953-1954 (Box 19)
  - College Antics - Saga Magazine 1960 (Box 20)
  - Collins, Floyd 1956 (Box 20)
  - "Comeback Trail" 1950 (Box 20)
  - Conerly, Charlie and Norman Van Brocklin 1958 (Box 20)
  - Contemporary Black 1971 (Box 20)
  - Corn Whiskey 1955 (Box 20)
  - Coroners - Corresponsence, Notes and Research 1953-1956 (Box 20)
  - Coroners - Manscript 1953-1956 (Box 20)
  - Corespondence 1956, 1957 (Box 20)
  - Cuba 1957 (Box 20)
  - Cured Cancer 1956-1960 (Box 21)
  - Daniels, Sophia K., M.D. 1953 (Box 21)
  - Davis, Al - Football Coach, The Citadel 1956 (Box 21)
  - "The Day the Boys Went to War" (The Battle of New Market) 1959-1962 (Box 21)
  - The Desegregated Heart Book Review 1962 (Box 21)
  - Dexedrine 1952 (Box 21)
  - Dexter, Harry 1952-1955 (Box 21)
  - Doniger, Harry 1954-1956 (Box 21)
  - Doolittle, Major James 1957 (Box 21)
  - Driver's Education 1956 (Box 21)
  - Drunk Driving 1955-1956 (Box 22)
  - Dukin, Eddy 1951-1952 (Box 22)
  - Durant, William (GM) 1957-1959 (Box 22)
  - Dvorak, August 1956 (Box 22)
  - Earhart, Amelia n.d. (Box 22)
  - Eaton, Cyrus 1957 (Box 22)
  - Etcheverry, Sam 1959-1961 (Box 22)
  - Everett, Elinor 1956-1957 (Box 22)
  - "Exhibition Game" - fiction sold n.d. (Box 22)
  - Faurot, Don 1956 (Box 22)
  - Fear in Greenwich Village - Rough Short Story n.d. (Box 22)
  - Federal Marshals 1962-1963 (Box 23)
  - Felerski, Max 1954 (Box 23)
  - Finks, Jim and Maxine 1956 (Box 23)
  - First Special Service Force 1962, n.d. (Box 23)
  - Fishing 1952 (Box 23)
  - Fisk University 1956 (Box 23)
  - Football n.d. (Box 23)
  - Football Novel n.d. (Box 23)
  - Football Old Timers n.d. (Box 23)
  - Football Stories 1957 (Box 23)
  - Foote Mineral Company 1956-1957 (Box 23)
  - Ford: Book Reviews 1969-1970 (Box 23)
  - Ford: Correspondence 1967-1972, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Ford: Correspondence with Weybright & Talley, Inc. Publishers 1967-1970 (Box 24)
  - Ford: Correspondence with the English Publisher, Cassell & Company, Ltd. 1967-1970 (Box 24)
  - Ford: Manuscripts (Galley Proofs) ca. 1969 (Box 24)
  - Ford: Notes and Research n.d. (Box 24)
  - Ford: Photograph Ideas n.d. (Box 24)
  - Franklin Library of American Enterprise 1955 (Box 24)
  - Frechette, Fred L. - Correspondence re: films 1967-1968 (Box 24)
  - Galveston, TX 1955 (Box 24)
  - "The Garden Under the Sun" (short story) n.d. (Box 24)
  - Gardening and Earthworms n.d. (Box 24)
  - "Georgette Herself" n.d. (Box 25)
  - Gifford, Frank 1961 (Box 25)
  - Glaser, Lewis (Quill Pen Man) 1957-1958 (Box 25)
  - Goodman, Al 1952 (Box 25)
  - "The Gorgeous Adventure" - prospectus for a book 1957-1961 (Box 25)
  - Goucher College Cuba Program 1953 (Box 25)
  - "The Great Aphrodisiac Myth" n.d. (Box 25)
  - Grey Cup (Canadian Rugby) 1960 (Box 25)
  - Gulf Coast 1955 (Box 25)
  - Hall, James W. (Bill) 1944-1962, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Hamby, Gordon Fawcett 1962 (Box 26)
  - "Happy Homecoming, Hoss" n.d. (Box 26)
  - Harris, John - Variety1955 (Box 26)
  - Harrison, Bob n.d. (Box 26)
  - Helicopters: Correspondence and Manuscript 1958-1959 (Box 26)
  - Helicopters: Drafts and Research n.d. (Box 26)
  - Hi-Fi Systems 1954-1955 (Box 26)
  - Highways 1953 (Box 26)
  - Hill Island 1961 (Box 26)
  - Hillsville, Virginia Courthouse Shooting 1959-1960 (Box 27)
  - Hoffman Borthers n.d. (Box 27)
  - Holzer, Hans - The Ghost Hunter 1961-1962 (Box 27)
  - Hot Springs, Arkansas 1953-1954 (Box 27)
  - "How to Build Your Own Church" - Correspondence, Research, Manuscript 1955-1956 (Box 27)
  - "How to Buy a Company" 1954 (Box 27)
  - "How to Invest $10,000" 1957-1958 (Box 27)
  - The Humor of John Kennedy- Correspondence 1967 (Box 27)
  - IBM 1971-1972 (Box 27)
  - Iceland 1950-1964, n.d., 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Indiana University Junior Division 1956 (Box 28)
  - Inter American University (Bootstrap U.) 1962, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - International Disposal Corporation (Stock Infomation) 1968-1970 (Box 28)
  - Inerstate Commerce Commission - Personal and Research 1954-1961, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Irish Research n.d. (Box 29)
  - Irvin, Mrs. Monty 1954 (Box 29)
  - Isometrics - Correspondence and Individual Sports 1963-1967, 1969, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Jai Alai 1954-1955 (Box 29)
  - Jenks, Jackson 1958-1962, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Johnson Murders (Mind reader who solved case) 1960 (Box 29)
  - Kappa Sigma Fraternity 1966-1969, n.d. (Box 30)
  - Karpman, Dr. Benjamin 1956 (Box 30)
  - Kelly, Alma C. 1949-1955 (Box 30)
  - Kemp, Jack and Frank Tripucka 1961 (Box 30)
  - King, Al and Tootsie ca. 1956 (Box 30)
  - Korean War Heroes 1963 (Box 30)
  - "The Labor Press" - Correspondence, Manuscripts and Research 1953 (Box 30)
  - Layne, Bobby n.d. (Box 30)
  - LeBaron, Eddie 1957-1962 (Box 30)
  - Leggett's - An American Success Story- Manuscript ca. 1980 (Box 30)
  - Leggett's - An American Success Story- Manuscript ca. 1980, 2 folders (Box 31)
  - "Let's Secede from Texas!" ca. 1963 (Box 31)
  - "Let's Trade Texas for Mexico" - Correspondence and Research re: Mexico and Texas 1952-1964, n.d., 2 folders (Box 31)
  - "Lincoln Road" - Manuscript and Research 1953 (Box 31)
  - Littauer and Wilkinson - Correspondence 1962-1969, n.d., 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Loewy, Edwin - The Giant Press Man 1958 (Box 32)
  - Louisville Council of Churches 1954 (Box 32)
  - Luce, Henry and Fulton Lewis, Jr. 1967 (Box 32)
  - "Make-It-Yourself Music" - Correspondence, Manuscript, Research 1956-1958 (Box 32)
  - "Margaret Bourke-White - "A Good-Looking American Girl" - Manuscript n.d. (Box 32)
  - Marriott, J. Willard 1970-1972 (Box 32)
  - McGuire, Frank 1961 (Box 32)
  - Miller School of Albemarle County, Virginia 1954-1955 (Box 32)
  - "The Millionaire who Played Left Field" 1954 (Box 32)
  - Milner, Dumas 1957-1958 (Box 32)
  - Mink 1957 (Box 32)
  - Minneapolis Lakers 1959-1960 (Box 33)
  - Moral Re-Armament (MRA) 1960 (Box 33)
  - Morris Plan 1971 (Box 33)
  - "Mortimer Caplin - The Man who Takes Your Money" in Saturday Evening Post 1962-1963 (Box 33)
  - Motels 1950-1953, n.d. (Box 33)
  - Muscular Dystrophy 1953-1960, n.d. (Box 33)
  - National Cash Register 1954 (Box 33)
  - National Exchange Club 1957, 1959 (Box 33)
  - National Urban League 1955-1957 (Box 33)
  - Newell Manufacturing 1968, 1972 (Box 34)
  - New Orleans (Acadia) 1958, 1960 (Box 34)
  - Novels n.d. (Box 34)
  - Ocean Shipping 1958, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Office and Bomb Shelter 1961-1964, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Okinawa 1959-1960 (Box 34)
  - Olivier, Sir Laurence 1961 (Box 34)
  - Outer Baldonia - Arundel, Russell 1949-1955 (Box 34)
  - Outer Banks, N.C. 1956 (Box 34)